radiantlifecatalog.com 2018-09-03

# Radiant Life | Ancient Wisdom for Modern Health

Protecting your privacy is important to us and we recognize that your information must be used responsibly. The following information will help you understand how Radiant Life collects, uses, and safeguards your personal information. If you have any questions that are not answered here, please contact us and we will answer them.

Our mailing/shipping address is:

Radiant Life  5277 Aero Drive Santa Rosa, CA 95403

We can be reached by telephone at: 888-593-9595

We can be reached by fax at: 707-433-8898 

We can be reached by email here.

### What information is collected?

**Personal Information**

Personal information is information that allows us to identify you. The types of Personal Information that we may collect from you includes, your name, home address, e-mail address, phone number, date of birth, and account information, such as your username, password, credit card information and other payment information.

We may collect personal information from you on or through the Web Site or Services in a variety of ways, including, when you register on the Web Site, purchase a product, participate in online giveaways or sign-up for a newsletter subscription or purchase merchandise.

**Device Identifiable Information**

We may collect information that does not identify you personally but is linked to your computer or device (Device Identifiable Information). We collect Device Identifiable Information from you in the normal course of operating our Website. When you visit our Website to browse, read or download information, we automatically collect information about your computer that your browser sends, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times, pages visited, and referring website addresses. We may use Device Identifiable Information we collect to analyze trends, help administer the Web Site, track the movement of visitors, to learn about and determine how much time visitors spend on each page of the Web Site, how visitors navigate throughout the Web Site or the Service and to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We may also collect Device Identifiable Information through "cookies” or "web beacons” as explained below.

We may also collect information about your mobile device such as the type and model, operating system e.g. iOS or Android, carrier name, mobile browser e.g. Chrome, Safari, applications using our Website, and identifiers assigned to your device, such as its iOS Identifier for Advertising (IDFA), Android Advertising ID (AAID), or unique device identifier (a number uniquely given to your device by your device manufacturer), sometimes referred to as a mobile carrier ID.

We may also collect your location information, such as your zip code or the approximate geographic area provided by your Internet service provider (ISP) or location positioning information provided by the location services and GPS features of your mobile device when location services have been enabled.

**Cookies**

To help us serve you better, we may collect Device Identifiable Information from you through technologies such as cookies and pixel tags (which are also called clear GIFs, web beacons, or pixels) or by tracking internet protocol (IP) addresses. Cookies are small data files that are stored by your web browser when you interact with a website. When you visit a webpage, the cookie sends back Device Identifiable Information. Pixel tags are small graphic images (usually invisible) that can be embedded in content and ads on a webpage that track usage of our Website and effectiveness of communication. These pixel tags can then be used to recognize our cookies and to monitor certain user interactions with a website. Cookies operate in the background, and you can turn them off if you wish by adjusting your Web browser settings, but doing so may impair your ability to use some of the features on the Web Site. We may use cookies to make the Web Site work better by, for example, remembering your preferences, keeping track of your login name, password and, if you want to buy items while on the Web Site, your shopping cart.

For more information, you may review the FTC’s guide to opting out of online tracking for computers and mobile devices. You can also see the Choice section below for ways to opt-out.

In some cases, we have arrangements with third-parties, such as authorized Service Providers, agents or representatives, to collect and store the foregoing information on our behalf, to provide services in connection with hosting or the operation of our Web Site, or to facilitate reporting of analytics (such as with Google Analytics).

Although the Device Identifiable Information that we share, including the Device Identifiable Information that is not linked to your mobile device, does not identify you personally there is a risk that third parties who receive such information from us may be able to re-identify you through other information they gather.

Except for IP Addresses, we may match Device Identifiable Information with Personal Information that we may have from or about you, which would allow us to identify you, we may use this information to provide you with offers that are available where you physically are located.

###  Site Security

We always use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving consumer data exchanged with our site. You can feel safe ordering online with Radiant Life. Any page on our site that handles sensitive information, such as your credit card number, is securely encrypted using the Secure Sockets layer (SSL) protocol. It's easy to know if a web site is secure. When you are accessing a secure website a closed lock will be displayed in the status bar of your browser window.

We use reasonable security efforts to protect the data in our possession. However, no method of transmission or storage of data is 100% secure and we will not be responsible for any damage that results from a security breach of data or the unauthorized access to or use of information, whether Personal Information or Device Identifiable Information. To the extent we provide your Personal Information to any third parties, we will request that they use reasonable security measures to protect your information.

### Social Media

When using the Services or when using certain third party social networking services e.g., Facebook, Twitter, Google + each a Social Network, you may have the option to connect your Service information and activity with your Social Network information and activity. If you authorize such a connection, you permit us to share or publish information about your Service activity with that Social Network and its users and to access certain of your Social Network information, as disclosed to you at the time you consent to the connection. Information we may share with a Social Network may include, but is not limited to: technical information about your Service activity, your Service comments or the videos you watch on Service. Information we may access about you, with your consent, from a Social Network may include, but is not limited to, your basic Social Network information, your location data, your list of contacts, friends or followers and certain information about your activities on the Social Network. If you permit a connection between a Social Network and a Service, we (and that Social Network) may be able to identify you and to associate information received pursuant to the connection with information we already have about you. For more information, please review the privacy disclosures and terms of your Social Network account, which govern how that account information is collected and shared with us.

### How we may use or disclose your information

We will not use, disclose, or share your information except as described in this Privacy Policy.

The Personal Information and Device Identifiable Information we collect from you may be used by us and by third-party service providers, such as hosting providers, data management companies, address list hosting companies, e-mail service providers, analytics companies, distribution companies, fulfillment companies and payment processors (collectively, Service Providers) for a variety of purposes, including to:

(i) contact you about the Web Site and/or Services you have requested; (ii) provide you with Services or information you have requested, or products or services you have ordered or signed up for, such as newsletters; (iii) confirm or fulfill an order you have made; (iv) administer your participation in a giveaway or promotion; (v) in order to facilitate the operation or maintenance of our Web Site, our Services, our operations and internal record keeping; and (vii) with your permission, send you promotional material or special offers. If you no longer wish to receive promotional e-mails from us, or have your information shared with third parties as previously described, you may change your mind and/or your preferences by following the directions in the Choices section of the Privacy Policy below.

Our Service Providers are given the information they need to perform their designated functions, and we do not authorize them to use or disclose Personal Information for their own marketing or other purposes.

Users may send information about our company, our products, our Services and/or our Web Site to their friends and family members by using an "E-mail to Friend" or similar feature on the Web Site or in an e-mail that we have sent them. We do not further contact those individuals without their consent to do so.

### Choices

You have various choices with respect to certain of our uses of the Personal Information we collect from you on or through the Web Site or Services. If you have not consented to us using your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy, we will only use it to complete the transaction or provide the service or product you have requested.

If you have agreed to receive communications or solicitations from us, but you later change your mind, you can revise your preferences on the Account section of the Web Site or email us at info@radiantlifecom. You also may opt out of receiving all future promotional e-mails from us by clicking on an opt-out or unsubscribe link within the promotional e-mail you receive. Please understand that if you opt out of receiving promotional correspondence from us, we may still contact you in connection with your relationship, activities, transactions, and communications with us.

You may opt-out of receiving ads from network advertisers by clicking the AdChoices icon on advertisements that are sent to you, visiting the opt-out pages on the NAI website (access the NAI’s opt-out tool) and the DAA website (access the DAA’s opt-out tool). Opting out does not prevent you from seeing ads; it simply means that network advertisers will no longer collect data for the purpose of providing you targeted ads. The DAA and NAI opt-out tools are cookie-based. They signal network advertisers so that they do not collect data online or deliver specific ads targeting you, and only affect the Internet/web browser on the computer where the cookies are installed. These opt-out tools will only function if your browser is set to accept third-party cookies. If you delete an opt-out cookie or all your cookies from a browser's cookie files, change web browsers or change computers, you will no longer be opted out of our data collection and ad targeting, and we may place a new cookie unless an opt-out cookie is again reset on that browser. Opting out using one browser on one computer will not opt you out using any other browser on the same or another computer.

### Accessing, reviewing, updating or correcting your personal information

If you want to access, review, update or correct inaccuracies in your Personal Information, you can revise your preferences on the Web Site or email us at info@radiantlife.com or write to us at Radiant Life 5277 Aero Drive Santa Rosa, CA 95403. Upon receiving your communication, we will take appropriate steps to update or correct such information in our possession or to remove you from our catalog and mailing list. Your preferences include, for example, your profile information, as well as any shipping, payment and account information (if applicable), as well as whether you want to receive communications from us. You can access your preferences by logging-in to your account. If you want to close your account with us and have us delete the Personal Information in it (except for information that we keep for record-keeping purposes), you should contact our Privacy Administrator. We may request certain Personal Information for the purposes of verifying the identity of the individual seeking access to their personal information records.

**Links to other websites and services**

The Web Site may contain links to other websites and online services. When you link to such other sites and services (including by means of clicking on hyperlinks, logos, widgets, banners or advertisements), you become subject to their terms of use and privacy policies posted thereon and/or applicable thereto. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third-party websites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you click on a link and leave the Web Site, and to read the privacy policies of every website that collects Personal Information from you.

### Additional information

Our Sites are operated and maintained within the U.S. We make no assurances or representations of any kind that the Sites are suitable for use outside the U.S. or in the country in which you reside. The information we collect is kept on servers in the U.S. and may be transferred to servers in other countries, subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We retain the Personal Information that we collect for so long as we continue to have a business purpose for it.

By accessing the Web Site, using a Service, establishing an account or making a purchase, you consent to the processing of your Personal Information as provided in this Privacy Policy. You may withdraw that consent by contacting us at info@radiantlife.com. You are required to provide certain Personal Information in order to use a Service, to make a purchase or to take advantage of certain features available through the Web Site. Your failure to provide such information may preclude you from using the Services or Web Site or may subject your account to termination, prevent you from making a purchase or prohibit you from using certain features.

If you wish to object to or raise a complaint about how we have handled your Personal Information, you may contact us at info@radiantlife.com.

### Changes in Policies

You should review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may modify it from time to time, and such changes will be effective upon our posting them to the Web Site. Where consistent with applicable law, your continued use of the Web Site and/or the Services after we have changed the Privacy Policy signifies your acceptance of the revised terms. Under certain circumstances (e.g., with respect to certain material changes to this Privacy Policy), we may also elect to notify you through additional means, such as posting a notice on the front page of the Web Site or by means of an e-mail that gives you the opportunity to indicate whether you consent to the proposed change.

### Concerns

If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at the above address or phone number, the Direct Marketing Association's Committee on Ethical Business Practices at [mgoldberger@the-dma.org](mailto:mgoldberger@the-dma.org), state or local chapters of the Better Business Bureau, state or local consumer protection offices, or the Federal Trade Commission by phone at 202-FTC-HELP

**Privacy Policy Updated May 24th, 2018**

[Proposition 65](http://oehha.ca.gov/proposition-65/general-info/proposition-65-plain-language) or the “Safe Drinking Water and Toxic Enforcement Act” is a unique California law that requires businesses to place a warning label on products that contain any one of a list of over 800+ different chemicals, even if these substances are naturally occurring and present in trace amounts.

Under this law, some of our foods and botanicals are required to carry the following notice:

 _Warning: This product contains chemicals known to the State of California to cause birth defects or reproductive harm._

Proposition 65 was an initiative originally passed in 1986 to address growing concerns about the dumping of toxic material into food and water supplies. Fundamentally this law is well-intentioned and supports environmental consciousness. However, in practice Prop 65 is often misconstrued and has brought with it many unforeseen consequences. Some of these effects have been challenging for small family companies like ours.

Any food grown on clean, organic-certified soil contains naturally occurring minerals in small amounts. The diverse spectrum of minerals in the soil—including calcium, iron and zinc—are taken up into plant material as part of the natural growth process. These nutrients are very important to our health and well being when obtained in appropriate amounts. At the right dose, these minerals help to support a wide range of bodily functions from building strong bones to supporting the brain. However, like any substance, they are not beneficial when taken in extreme quantities.

Soil also contains minuscule amounts of metals. These too are not harmful when consumed in tiny amounts and can in fact be perfectly healthy. Virtually all foods grown in the earth’s rich, healthy soils have the potential to include small quantities of metals like lead and cadmium.

It is important to keep in mind that the metals found in plants are altogether different than the heavy metals that are mined, chemically treated and concentrated for use in industrial products. Obviously, these industrial metals should be carefully kept out of our air, water and food supplies. However the benign metals found in clean, fresh produce are not a threat. They are present in tiny amounts, bound and integrated into the plant fibers—where they have always been and will stay.

Nonetheless lead is one of the most frequently cited chemicals in Prop 65. Levels exceeding 0.5 micrograms require a label. This is approximately 1,000 times lower than the amount known to cause reproductive harm according to the federal government. Because these levels are hard to assess and regulate in any given product, many manufacturers have made the choice to label all products that could even just possibly have lead in them. This includes some of our Superfood Supplements and Nutrient Dense Foods. Labeling in this way helps to safeguard against potential lawsuits in California, but it does not mean that the products themselves are unsafe.

Numerous industries have found Proposition 65 difficult to comply with. Not only are regulations hard to follow, but enforcement has been difficult and inconsistent. It is also important to note that because Prop 65 was passed by a ballot initiative, it falls outside of the usual legislative process and is difficult to update or change in anyway.

Prop 65 is enforced entirely by way of civil lawsuits brought on by organizations and, on some occasions, by the state’s attorney general. These suits can be crippling and resource-draining for small companies. Stakes for settlements are high and proceedings can involve considerable sums of money.

In an attempt to prevent legal action of any kind, many companies have opted to post Prop 65 labels and signs. Warning signs appear all over the state of California in restaurants, banks, hotels, gas stations, and all other facilities that could even just possibly contain traces of any one of the 800 chemicals mentioned in the law.

Other companies may elect not to provide warnings because, in their assessment, they conclude they are in full compliance with Prop 65 and are willing to take the risk of legal action. Two identical products can therefore have labeling differences simply because of company philosophy.

Even though Prop 65 was designed for use in California only, you may receive products with warnings on them even if you are not a resident of this state. This is because our company is based in California, and all of our shipping and receiving facilities are also located here. When manufacturers send us goods, they are required to add Prop 65 warming labels before those products can enter state lines. We have made the choice to leave these stickers on the packages regardless of their final destination. In the end we decided that our resources are best spent on finding ways to bring you the best organic products on the market, not on removing these stickers. We hope you understand!

We follow a very strict set of purity guidelines when selecting products to become part of our catalog. Long before products even make it to our shelves, they undergo rigorous analysis and testing. Our team works very closely with our suppliers to ensure that safety standards are met along each step of the way, from how foods are farmed to how they are prepared, packaged and delivered to your door. This type of ongoing monitoring and research is at the very heart of our business model. To read more about our standards, visit our About Us page.

If you have remaining questions or concerns regarding Prop 65 or our company safety policies, don’t hesitate to call 888-593-8333 or contact us here.
